Fortnightly Club Papers WLU.Coll.0671
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
Fortnightly Club Papers
Inclusive 1930-2015
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
WLU.Coll.0671
4 Linear Feet
- Meeting Minutes
- Papers
  Arrangement
  The papers are arranged alphabetically by author's last name, except for the 2014-2015 papers which are housed in a separate binder comingled with meeting minutes and paper responses.
  - Edward C. Atwood, Jr., 1974-1985; Atwood, Edward Charles, Jr.; 3 Item
    - Doomsday!, 1977-01-21; Atwood, Edward Charles, Jr.
      Economics; Malthusianism; Conservation of natural resources; Ricardo, David, 1772-1823; Malthus, T. R. (Thomas Robert), 1766-1834; Club of Rome
    - The Economic Impact of Washington and Lee University on the City of Lexington, 1974-03-15; Atwood, Edward Charles, Jr.
      University towns -- Economic aspects; Economics
    - I Owe You or More than You Wanted to Know About the National Debt, Atwood, Edward Charles, Jr.
      Debts, Public
    - The Last Man who Knew Everything: Thorstein Bunde Veblen, 1985-02-15; Atwood, Edward Charles, Jr.
      Economics; Sociology; Philosophy; Veblen, Thorstein, 1857-1929
  - Colonel George Ax, 1986-03-28; Ax, George, Colonel; 1 Item
    - Elias Boudinot, America's First President, 1986-03-28; Ax, George, Colonel
      Huguenots -- Genealogy; Huguenots; French Americans; Boudinot, Elias, 1740-1821; College of New Jersey (Princeton, N.J.)
  - Lee D. Badgett, 1992-1994; Badgett, Lee D; 2 Item
    - Men of Brass, 1992-03-20; Badgett, Lee D
      Brass rubbing; Sculpture, Gothic; Bronze sculpture, Renaissance
    - The Woolmerchant. the Dean, and the Gothic Revival, 1994-02-04; Badgett, Lee D
      Brass rubbing; Gothic revival (Art); Brasses; Brasses, Victorian; Liddel, Duncan, 1561-1613; Pugin, Augustus Welby Northmore, 1812-1852
  - John G Barrett, 1984-1994; Barrett, John Gilchrist; 5 Item
    - William Tecumseh Sherman, 1986-11-14; Barrett, John Gilchrist
      Military ethics; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891; Mahan, D. H. (Dennis Hart), 1802-1871; Adams, J. (Jasper), 1793-1841; Kent, James, 1763-1847
    - High Rents and Better Encouragement - the Highland Seats of North Carolina 1732-1776, Barrett, John Gilchrist
      Scots; Scottish Americans; Scotland--Highlands; American loyalists; North Carolina--Cape Fear River Valley; Gilchrist, John, Sr., 1740-1802
    - The Navy's Secret Weapon, 1989-01-20; Barrett, John Gilchrist
    - College Days, August 1941 - August 1943, 1994-10-14; Barrett, John Gilchrist
      North Carolina -- Ridgeway; Wake Forest College; Franks, Jesse D., Jr., 1919-1943
    - I Lied, VMI in the Civil War, 1984-10-5; Barrett, John Gilchrist
      Virginia Military Institute; Jackson, Stonewall, 1824-1863
  - G.L. Barton, 1934; Barton, G. L.; 1 Item
    - Jack Jouett's Ride, 1934-02-16; Barton, G. L.
      Virginia--Cuckoo Tavern; Jouett, Jack, 1754-1822
  - George R. Bent, 2005-2013; Bent, George R.; 4 Item
    - The Fly, 2005-03-04; Bent, George R.
      Painting, Netherlandish; Painting, Renaissance; Christus, Petrus, approximately 1410-1472 or 1473
    - Paintings, Protection, and Prosecution, 2008-12-03; Bent, George R.
      Madonna della Tromba; Jacopo, del Casentino, -approximately 1358
    - Reassessing the Code, 2010-12-01; Bent, George R.
      Leonardo, da Vinci, 1452-1519
    - The 500 year-old Lady, 2013-02-06; Bent, George R.
      Mona Lisa (Leonardo, da Vinci); Leonardo, da Vinci, 1452-1519; Salai, Andrea, approximately 1480-1524; Del Giocondo, Lisa, 1479-
    - The Art Show that Felled a Presidency, 2008-03-19; Bent, George R.
      Performance art; College of William & Mary; Nichols, Gene, 1951-
  - Gordon R. Beyer, 1987-2004; Beyer, Gordon R; 8 Item
    - "We hold these Truths to be self-evident...", Beyer, Gordon R
      Slavery; Transatlantic slave trade
    - Waltz Me Around Again, Willy, 1987-12-11; Beyer, Gordon R
      Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959; Marshall Plan; Obote, A. Milton (Apollo Milton), 1924-2005
    - It's Time to Reassess the Operations of AID, 1989-11-17; Beyer, Gordon R, 1930-2010
      Marshall Plan
    - America, Japan and the Atomic Bomb, 1993-02-19; Beyer, Gordon R, 1930-2010
      World War (1939-1945); War crimes; Hirohito, Emperor of Japan, 1901-1989
    - The Who?, 1995-03-17; Beyer, Gordon R, 1930-2010
      Makonde (African people); Sculpture, Makonde; Mapiko (Dance drama)
    - Venona, 1998-11-06; Beyer, Gordon R, 1930-2010
      Venona project; Cryptography; United States. Army. Signal Intelligence Service
    - A Remarkable Man, 2000-10-07; Beyer, Gordon R, 1930-2010
      Washington, George, 1732-1799
    - Last Train to Paradise, 2004; Beyer, Gordon R, 1930-2010
      Flagler, Henry Morrison, 1830-1913
  - Laurent Boetsch, 1997-2012; Boetsch, Howard Laurent; 2 Item
    - Women and Song, 1997-01-10; Boetsch, Howard Laurent
      Spain; Wine and wine making; Wine industry
    - JC, the Brief, 2012-01-18; Boetsch, Howard Laurent
      Franco, Francisco, 1892-1975
  - D.E. Brady, 1972-1998; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.; 7 Item
    - The Gahidoghson, 1972-03-17; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Virginia--James River; Erosion; Agriculture; Hydroelectric power plants; Water mills
    - Explorations for a Railroad to the Pacific, 1973-11-02; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
    - The Camille Flood - 1969, 1979; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
    - The Coal Slurry Pipeline, 1984-02-03; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Coal slurry pipelines; Coal; Coal-fired power plants; Railroads
    - From Springfield to Zack, 1986-03-14; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Virginia--Rockbridge County--Springfield; Virginia--Rockbridge County--Zach; Virginia -- Brownsburg; Virginia--Rockbridge County--Rapp's Mill; Virginia--Rockbridge County--Murat; Virginia--Rockbridge County--Summers; Virginia--Rockbridge County--Oak Bank; Virginia--Rockbridge County--Old Balcony Falls; Virginia -- Collierstown; Virginia--Rockbridge County--Buffalo Bend; Virginia--Buena Vista; Virginia -- South River; Virginia--Rockbridge County--Navel Flats
    - The Buffalo Forge, 1991-10-04; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Virginia -- Buffalo Forge; Wrought-iron
    - Damnation, 1998-01-09; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Dams; Hydroelectric generators; China--San Xia Dam
  - D.E. Brady, 1975-1993; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.; 8 Item
    - Our Weather, 1975-10-17; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Jet stream; Glacial epoch
    - William Wilson Ironmonger, 1978-02-17; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Weaver, William
    - The North River Navigation Co., 1987-03-13; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
    - Iron Valley Revisited, 1989-10-20; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Virginia -- South River; Iron ores; Iron founding; Geography
    - Irish Creek, 1981-11; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Virginia -- Irish Creek
    - Save the Bay, 1993-10-22; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Atlantic Ocean--Chesapeake Bay; Silt; Fertilizer industry -- Waste disposal; Pesticides; Nutrient pollution of water; Blue Plains Sewage Treatment Plant (Washington, D. C.)
    - North River Navigation Company, 1987-02-1996-02; Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
      Virginia--Maury River; Canals; Virginia -- James River and Kanawha Canal; North River Navigation Company
    - Unknown Title, Brady, Douglas Ellinipsico, Jr.
  - George M. Brooke, 1968-2011; Brooke, George M., Jr.; 7 Item
    - The Florence Flood, 1968-01-19; Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Italy -- Florence; Italy--Arno River Valley
    - The 1936 Mutiny, 1970-01-23; Brooke, George M., Jr.
    - The Heavenly Kingdom, 1976-02-06; Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Taiping Rebellion; Qing Dynasty (China); Hong, Xiuquan, 1814-1864; Yang, Xiuqing, -1856
    - The Gypsies, 1982-02-19; Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Romanies
    - The City of Lions, 1990-01-19; Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Singapore; Raffles, Thomas Stamford, Sir, 1781-1826; Lee, Kuan Yew, 1923-2015
    - Bruno and The Valley, 2011-02-16; Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Bigeard, Marcel-Maurice, 1916-2010
    - The City of Lions, Brooke, George M., Jr.
  - George M. Brooke, 1983-2013; Brooke, George M., III; Brooke, George M., Jr.; 7 Item
    - Salt Water to Fresh, 1983-12-02; Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Uganda Railway; Imperial British East Africa Company; Patterson, J. H. (John Henry), 1867-1947
    - The Old Corps, 1985-12-13; Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Virginia Military Institute
    - The Old Corps, Again, 1991-10-18; Brooke, George M., Jr.
    - A Tale of One of Our Own: John M. Brooke and His Pacific Cruise and Japanese Adventure, 1858-1860, 2008-01-20; Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Scope and Contents
      Included with this paper is George M. Brooke's paper on the Karin Maru's journey to the United States of America, published in 1960 for The American Neptune Vol. 20, No. 3.
      Guano industry; USS Fenimore Cooper; Kanrin Maru (Ship); Brooke, John M. (John Mercer), 1826-1906; Heco, Joseph, 1837-1897
    - The Most Wonderful Athlete in the World, 2013-02-20; Brooke, George M., III
      Thorpe, Jim, 1887-1953
    - Why do They Shake?, Brooke, George M., Jr.
      Shakers; Lee, Ann, 1736-1784
    - The Voyage of the Kanrin Maru, 1860: and Episode in American Naval Diplomacy, Brooke, George M., Jr.
  - Charles F. Brower, 2011; Brower, Charles F; 1 Item
    - Role of a Lifetime, 2011-02-02; Brower, Charles F
    - Demon of Integrity, 2009-09-30 (Box 5)
  - William Buchanan, 1985-1999; Buchanan, William; 6 Item
    Psychometrics; Statistics; Galton, Francis, 1822-1911
    - Intelligence?, 1985-10-18; Buchanan, William
    - C, 1990; Buchanan, William
      Espionage; Great Britain. MI6; Cumming, Mansfield, Sir, 1859-1923; Sinclair, Hugh M. (Hugh Macdonald), 1910-1990; Menzies, Stewart Graham, Sir, 1890-1968
    - Campaign Polling, 1996-10-11; Buchanan, William
    - Eugenics, 1999-03-15; Buchanan, William
    - Eugenics, 1999-03-25; Buchanan, William
      Eugenics; Galton, Francis, 1822-1911; Buck, Carrie, 1906-1983; Bell, John H. (John Hendren), 1883-1934; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894; Hoyt, William Dana, 1880-1945; Baird, Bill, b. 1932; Eisenstadt, Thomas S. (Thomas Stephen), b. 1936
    - Machines who Think, Buchanan, William
      Computers; ENIAC (Computer); Univac computer; Artificial intelligence; Turing test; General Problem Solver; McCorduck, Pamela, 1940-2021; Babbage, Charles, 1791-1871; Hollerith, Herman, 1860-1929; Von Neumann, John, 1903-1957; Turing, Alan, 1912-1954
  - William Buchanan, 1980-1995; Buchanan, William; 8 Item
    - The Wrong Experts, 1980-03-28; Buchanan, William
    - Polls Apart, 1984-03-30; Buchanan, William
    - Since Ulta, 1987-10-16; Buchanan, William; 2 Item
    - Portrait of an Orator, 1991-12-10; Buchanan, William
    - Scientific Politics, 1993; Buchanan, William
    - Ulta and the Battle of the Atlantic, 1994-10-07; Buchanan, William
    - The Secret Ladies' Basement: Washington and Lee's Contribution to Civil Defense, 1953-1976, 1995-06-07; Buchanan, William
    - Prewar W&L, 1995-08-20; Buchanan, William
  - Henry D. Campbell, 1932; Campbell, Henry Donald; 2 Item
    - The Valley of Virginia, 1932-05-09; Campbell, Henry Donald
    - The Valley of Virginia, Campbell, Henry Donald
  - P. Allan Carlsson, 1972-2012; Carlsson, P. Allan; 6 Item
    - Don't Look Homeward, Kristina, 1972-12-15; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - (LxW)/3 X H, 1983-10-07; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - East of Jordan, 1985-10-04; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - The Heart of the Maghreb, 1989-10-06; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - Christopher Who?, 1991-11-15; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - The Family Profession, 2010-03-03
    - A Danish Socrates, 2012-02-29; Carlsson, P. Allan
  - P. Allan Carlsson, 1970-1993; Carlsson, P. Allan; 7 Item
    - New Sweden, 1970-10-23; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - Philosophy and Temperament, 1976-01; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - Inca Safari, 1979-10-05; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - Lord Deliver Us, Carlsson, P. Allan
    - Mid- Med Malta: Islands in the Middle of the Mediterranean, Carlsson, P. Allan
    - Mid-eighteenth Century Trip to North America, 1993-11-05; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - The Philosopher, Carlsson, P. Allan
  - P. Allan Carlsson, 1974-2008; Carlsson, P. Allan; 6 Item
    - The Viking Mystery, 1974-11-30; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - A Symphony For Travelers in A Mirror, 1987-11-13; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - A Swede in the Sandwich Islands, 1995-11-17; Carlsson, P. Allan
      Fornander, Abraham, 1812-1887
    - Two-Faced Philosophy, 2006-01; Carlsson, P. Allan
    - The Disenfranchised, 2008-03-05
    - What's With Secretary Watt?, Carlsson, P. Allan
    - The Via Egnatia, Carlsson, P. Allan
  - N. D. Chapman, 1950; Chapman, N. D.; 1 Item
    - Playing Josephus, 1950-10-06; Chapman, N. D.
  - Edward L. Claiborn, 1991-2003; Claiborn, Edward L.
    - That Proverbial Horseshoe Nail, 1991-02-15; Claiborn, Edward L.
    - The Cambridge Spies, Claiborn, Edward L.
    - BUT IT DOESN'T GLITTER!, 1992-10-23; Claiborn, Edward L.
    - Flights of Fancy or Come Fly With Me, 1995-02-17; Claiborn, Edward L.
    - So,... What's the Difference?, 1996-11-08; Claiborn, Edward L.
    - From Virginia to Idaho, 1803-1805, 1999-02-05; Claiborn, Edward L.
    - Montana 2000: No Campfires Allowed, 2001-02-16; Claiborn, Edward L.
    - A Modern-Day Tale of Icarus, 2003-02-28; Claiborn, Edward L.
  - Prof. Sydney Coulling, 1976-1984; Coulling, Sidney Mathias Baxter, III; 5 Item
    - The Importance of Being Gay, 1976-10-15; Coulling, Sidney Mathias Baxter, III
    - A Seventeenth-Century Original: The Life and Writings of Sir Thomas Browne (1605-1682), 1979-02-02; Coulling, Sidney Mathias Baxter, III
    - The Apostle of Culture Visits Richmond, 1984-11-16; Coulling, Sidney Mathias Baxter, III
    - A Tale of Two Citizens, Coulling, Sidney Mathias Baxter, III
      Woolf, Virginia; Woolf, Leonard
    - "Old Rex", Coulling, Sidney Mathias Baxter, III
  - Lloyd R. Craighill, 1964-1966; Craighill, Lloyd R.
    - Rural Roots, 1964-11-06; Craighill, Lloyd R.
    - Missionary Contribution to Hawaiian Civilization, 1966-11-04; Craighill, Lloyd R.
  - Edwin D. Craun, 1992-1995; Craun, Edwin David
    - MS., 1992-11-20; Craun, Edwin David
    - Speaking The Thing That Is Not, 1994-08; 1995-01-20; Craun, Edwin David
  - Ollinger Crenshaw, Crenshaw, Ollinger
    - Old Washington College: Two Episodes, Crenshaw, Ollinger
    - A Virginia Whig in the Crisis of 1860-1861, Crenshaw, Ollinger
      Botts, John Minor
  - Lloyd Davidson, 1957-1988
    - Kinds of Literary Study, 1957-01-19
    - Joseph Conrad, 1963-02-08
      Conrad, Joseph
    - British Universities, 1964-11-20
    - Mimesis, 1966-12-02
    - The Cult of the Irrational, 1971-02-05
    - Grand Tour at 60, 1972-10-20
    - Mare Nostrum, 1979-03-16
    - Aegean Island of the Sun, 1983-01-28
    - Lady C After Fifty Years, 1985-01-18
    - Cycles and Singularities, 1988-10-07
    - The Superior Student, 1959-03-06
    - Some Thoughts Concerning Basic Issues in Current Educational Policy, 1961-03-03
    - Relevance in Higher Education, 1968-12-05
    - Tragic and Comic, 1975-03-07
    - Yeats: The Problem of Poetry and Belief, 1976-10-01
    - What's In A Name?, 1980-12-12
    - Renaissance Man?, 1987-01-16
  - Thomas W. Davis, 1987-2013
    - "The most typical Englishman of all time....", 1987-02-27
    - Reflection on '...this scepter'd isle', 1990-12-14
    - In the Beginning, 1998-11-20
    - JJ + RC = WLSC, 2005-03-18
    - What I Miss, 2009-03-18
    - A Truly Remarkable Woman, 2013-03-20
    - Comments as First Respondent to Mr. Davis's Paper, "JJ + RC = WLSC", 2005-03-18
    - Home for Christmas, 1992-12-04
    - Because It's Round,...., 1995-02-03
    - Hank and Babe, Ted and Drina, 2001
    - Ask Not, 2004-02-13
    - 111 Years and Largely Unchanged, 2011-03-16
  - Barton Dick, 1986
    - Ouch! That Medical Bill Hurts!
    - A Triumph of Technology over Judgement?, 1986-01-31
  - David Ellington, 2006-2012; Ellington, David
    - Dark Water, Dark Mind, 2006-02-24; Ellington, David
    - Sinister Minds, 2012-01-04; Ellington, David
    - The Most Beautiful Pearl, 2008-01-09
    - Bo to Mo, Are You Crazy?, 2010-03-17
  - John W. Elrod, 1986; Elrod, John W.
    - A Literary Cripple, 1986-10-17; Elrod, John W.
  - McCluer Gilliam, 1965
    - Reinhold Niebuhr's Politics, 1965-03-19
      Niebuhr, Reinhold
    - Wailing Wall Woes, 1968-04-15
    - Israel, 1969-03-07
    - 1874-1974, 1975-01-10
  - Robert Glidden, 2012
    - Food or Fuel?, 2012-12-05
  - Timothy P. Golden, 2009-2013
    - The Launch, 2009-01-07
    - Manners Matter, 2011-01-05
    - A Fish Story, 2013-01-09
  - Joseph Goldsten, 1994-1996; Goldsten, Joseph
    - The Modern Industrial Revolution: A Few Dimensions, 1994-03-18; Goldsten, Joseph
    - The Evolution of Tax Reform, 1996-02-20; Goldsten, Joseph
  - Fred Hadsel, 1978-2001; Hadsel, Fred L.; 7 Item
    - Lalibela, 1978-11-17; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - Elephants for Worst of Towns, 1987-02-13; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - The London Stage, 1990-11-30; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - The Modern Map of Africa, 1996-01-19; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - Heart of Darkness, 2001-03-10; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - La Grande Encyclopedie, Hadsel, Fred L.
    - City in the Sand, Hadsel, Fred L.
  - Fred Hadsel, 1983-1996; Hadsel, Fred L.; 6 Item
    - Third Assistant Spear Carrier, 1983-03-11; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - Ulysses, 1988-11-04; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - War as Memory, 1993-03-19; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - Then, Yes. Now, No., 1995-01-06; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - Wyoming Valley, 1996-10-25; Hadsel, Fred L.
    - Solomon and Sheba - the Ethiopian Myth, Hadsel, Fred L.
  - Dick Halseth, 2012; Halseth, Dick; 1 Item
    - The Franklin Society and Library Co., 2012-03-14; Halseth, Dick
  - James C. Hanes, 1964-1974; Hanes, James C.; 6 Item
    - Earthquakes - U.S.A., 1964-11; Hanes, James C.
    - Controlled Development, 1963-01-18; Hanes, James C.
    - In the Beginning..., 1967-01-20; Hanes, James C.
    - The Great River - The Rio Grande, 1969-01-24; Hanes, James C.
    - Claude Crozet and Early Railroads in Virginia, 1974-11-1; Hanes, James C.
      Crozet, Claudius, 1790-1864
    - In the Beginning..., Hanes, James C.
  - James C. Hanes, 1955-1972; Hanes, James C.; 5 Item
    - The Origins of Foreign Operations Administrations, 1955-03-11; Hanes, James C.
    - The Ways of Man, 1956-12-14; Hanes, James C.
    - Maya and Copan, 1961-01-20; Hanes, James C.
    - The James River Canal, 1970-12-04; Hanes, James C.
    - The Sons of Martha, 1972-12-01; Hanes, James C.
  - Bruce Herrick, 1994-2005; Herrick, Bruce Hale, Dr., 1936 - 2012; 5 Item
    - The World Bank at 50, 1994-11-18; Herrick, Bruce Hale, Dr., 1936 - 2012
    - Priceless Beauty?, 1999-10-29; Herrick, Bruce Hale, Dr., 1936 - 2012
    - Priceless Beauty?, 1999-01-22; Herrick, Bruce Hale, Dr., 1936 - 2012
    - Social Indicators, 2003-10-17; Herrick, Bruce Hale, Dr., 1936 - 2012
    - Half of God's Existence, 2005-09-30; Herrick, Bruce Hale, Dr., 1936 - 2012
  - Farris Hotchkiss, 1973-1981; Hotchkiss, Farris Pierson; 4 Item
    - Transactional Analysis: Pop or not?, 1973-03-16; Hotchkiss, Farris Pierson
    - A School Teacher Named Jed, 1974-10-04; Hotchkiss, Farris Pierson
    - A Jack of All Trades and a Painter, Too, 1977-12-16; Hotchkiss, Farris Pierson
    - First Across the Atlantic, 1981-03-20; Hotchkiss, Farris Pierson
  - James L. Howe, 1910-1952; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.; 5 Item
    - The Fortnightly Club, 1921-03-18; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - Culture and Chemistry, 1932-02-19; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - Bits of Old China and New, 1934-02-16; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - Unknown Title, Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - The College Problem, Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
  - James L. Howe, 1910-1940; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.; 5 Item
    - Industrial Norway, 1910-10-07; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - An Old New England Town, 1938-03-04; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - George Washington Curtis Lee, 1940-10; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
      Lee, George Washington Custis
    - General George Washington Custis Lee and the Grace Memorial Church, Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - George Mason of Gunston Hall, Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
      Mason, George
  - James L. Howe, 1912-1952; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.; 4 Item
    - The Postal Service of the Confederacy, 1912-10-18; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - The Revolution of 1848 in Germany, 1944-02-18; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - Pure Food Legislation, Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - Reminiscences of a Nonagenarian, 1952-12-14
  - James L. Howe, 1936-1948; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.; 4 Item
    - The Weed that Set the World on Fire, 1936-02-28; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - Washington and Lee University and the Morrill Act, 1946-12-06; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - Sequoiya, 1948-10-29; Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
    - What is an Atom?, Howe, James Lewis, Jr.
  - R.E.R. Huntley, 1974-1986; Huntley, Robert E. R. (Robert Edward Royall); 2 Item
    - Independent Colleges and the State, 1971-11-19; Copy; Huntley, Robert E. R. (Robert Edward Royall)
    - Whose John: The Impact of the Equal Rights Amendment, 1974-02-01; Huntley, Robert E. R. (Robert Edward Royall)
  - General Richard Irby, 1976-1986; Irby, General Richard
    - The Old Army, Irby, General Richard
    - Recollections of Men, Places, and Events, 1845-1900, 1976-04-02; Irby, General Richard
    - Valor, 1986-02-28; Irby, General Richard
  - Leonard E. Jarrard, 1980-2012; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - On Memory, 1980-10-17; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - The Cholinergic Connection, 1984-11-30; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - Love or Eugenics or How Far Should We Go?, 1986-11-28; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - Saturnism, 1991-12-06; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - On Bologna, 1994-11; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - Fountain of Youth?, 1998-12-04; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - On Stem Cells, 2002-12-06; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - The Imperial City, 2004-11-12; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - On Music and the Brain, 2008-11-14; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - On Alzheimer's, 2010-10; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
    - The Poorhouse, 2012-11-14; Jarrard, Leonard Everett
  - William A. Jenks, 1963-1965; Jenks, William Alexander
    - The Right, 1963-03-22; Jenks, William Alexander
    - Archduke Franz Ferdinand, 1965-01-08; Jenks, William Alexander
  - Lewis G. John, 1981-2011; John, Lewis George
    - His Superfluous Excellency, 1989-02-03; John, Lewis George
    - The Fall of the Iron Lady, 1991-11-01; John, Lewis George
    - First Respondent on Generational Equity, 1995-10-03; Goldsten, Joseph
    - Generational Equity, 1995-10-06; John, Lewis George
    - Clinton Cloned?, 1998-01-23; John, Lewis George
    - An Epic Friendship, 2005-12-02; John, Lewis George
    - Back to 18?, 2007-11-28
    - The Noble Experiment, 2011-10-12; John, Lewis George
    - Reflections on Leadership, 1981-03-06; John, Lewis George
    - Suavity in Modo, Fortiter in Re (Gently in Manner, Strong in Deed), 1983-02-25; John, Lewis George
    - Why 21?, 1985-03-15; John, Lewis George
    - The Revolution of the Iron Lady, 1987-02-02; John, Lewis George
    - Prescription for Change, 1993-10-08; John, Lewis George
    - A Tale of Two Elections, 2001-11-02; John, Lewis George
    - Right Again?, 2004-02-27; John, Lewis George
    - Remarks of J. Hardin Marion, As First Respondent of Mr. John's Paper, 2004-02-27; Marion, John Hardin
    - Mr. Ponzi's Scheme, 2009-12-02; John, Lewis George (Box 5)
    - The Noble Experiment, 2001-10-12; John, Lewis George
  - Gen. Charles E. Kilbourne, 1949; Kilbourne, Charles E., General, 1872-1963
    - Democracy, 1949-02-04; Kilbourne, Charles E., General, 1872-1963
  - John W. Knapp, 1984-2012
    - Latin's Light Dragoons, 1986-10-03
    - Designed To Be Permanent, 1996-12-06